Hi sob
kyuhee bom in light and outsiders
program as you have heard
in the announcement for this program
I started reading this
series with my teacher Khan rinpoche
about
trivago already this is about 35 years
ago and he said I want to
learn teach you about
this unusual book then I thought
Wow what book is this then he said this
is a poem and it was written about
300-350 years ago
or 375 years ago
and it was written by the first pancen lama
whose name is lobsang Suci gold I Love
You
from me I love him very much He
is an extraordinary teacher
I was with him for 3 years
and during that time
he was teacher Adan he is a
very extraordinary poet
we also translated his
secret poems
I translated many of them
a friend of mine
John
published it without my permission
although This is a secret silent
publishing without permission indeed His poems are
very good regarding the one
that discusses iadoa from Cannon pouch he
also wrote many philosophy books
so
I really like his depiction
of how the human body turns
into a living gem or diamond
which is written very clearly
High shadowfight vanilin
which he called Transformation of the five
parts of the body and mind perhaps
someday we can review it
together
he also wrote a
very famous lamrim called gelem
ndut
if semen iseepassword
means a journey to a
pleasure that can be found at the beginning
this is
an advanced level essay on the
first three western chapters
I was thinking about how to
teach those lessons
to more people
[Music]
so today Let's
look at this poem I started reading
this poem 11 years ago and I
also Started translating it
we have a defynik program
Verizon at&t
lately
www.message.com there is a
famous arboretum there
called Aini arboretum means a
garden for the public or for the public in
Arizona we don't have a garden
it's just
cactus
Indah menyusu go-send started teaching this
11 years ago
and when my teacher taught
me this book
I
heard Miko someone lit
My teacher had some obstacles
to finish this book so
we didn't have time to finish it
together then he passed away
in
Indonesia and I'm trying to
finish everything and
translate it because it's so beautiful
so Let me  tell a little bit
so the angel in this story is
our understanding of the pen
but in this poem
I feel this angel is a
very
beautiful person very beautiful that describes
our thoughts that are on the good side
in my country when we grow up
online outsiders program they will
show us a photo
like the one you saw earlier in the
announcement Aa on the screen that is there is an
angel and there is a devil the
devil inside me always
wants me to eat donuts
while the
angel inside me wants me to
eat vegetables they always fight
every day
and the devil says Wow it would be nice
if we could eat donuts it's been 2-3
weeks we haven't eaten donuts
even though I know they donuts It's
not good for your body
but yes that's one of the pleasures
in life
and If you eat donuts once in a while it's
okay too
then the angel says Wow maybe
whatever you eat becomes you
You are what you eat
and every time you eat something
unhealthy becomes part of
your body and yesterday we
taught
an interesting teaching that
said that you are what you
eat
because what you eat becomes your body
so my body today
ah wait I'm cooking soup for
my wife
but bokg
this Sunday  we both got covert but
I recovered first and he was still a bit
sick so I had time for him to become a
VCD
so the devil wants you to eat donuts
and the Angel says maybe
Let's just eat vegetables then they
will fight in your mind
and this is what happens in this poem
except the angel here
is our understanding of the pen
and every time we teach about
the pen
I want
I want to
grab you from the Zoom screen and
want to say Have you understood yet
Have you understood yet because this is
a truth
that everyone in this world is logical
if we really
use logic after me and the
theory of the pen to you when I
hold
a Pen in front of you
I see the pen is very very
simple
When I Show the same pen
to a dog then they AHe
will want to
bite it he doesn't
see the pen at all this is like a story
we tell children maybe
the team can write a book for children
entitled this pen is like a
children's story but actually it is not this
is 100% proof that If
your mind is really clean and pure as
you can see it is proof
that everything comes from
ourselves not from outside and I do
n't know this seems simple
but we need to repeat it  1000
times I think you might be tired of
listening to the Pen Story But if
you really understand then you know
that you can change the whole world
and we have a word in
Buddhist teachings called Mandala which
means a perfect world no
war no sickness no
death
no sadness that
if this pen is right
then Mandala is also right and maybe we
can change the world
and you listen to places
like eh Mbak Fir Daus or heaven
amitabha
Henry godain sterilization then we
think is there really such a thing
there are people who say to me Oh
gecella heaven will be very boring
every day the same thing nothing
fun
listverse Then there are more stupid people
who say ah heaven does not exist
because we only know
ABD al-hayy good when we
see bad things I even
heard some people explain
that this is
a what we call an
origin that depends on something else
in my opinion such an opinion is wrong
and stupid paint is the same as we
say we can not eat an apple
without eating a pineapple when that is not
true
You can eat an apple Even if you do not
eat a pineapple it is something that is very
possible if this pen comes
from me then I can create
perfect world we can
do it there are indeed places
like amitabha heaven
and the people who go there have already
finished taking classes like this a long time
ago In fact they are no
different from us
Buddhas bodhisattvas
they started the same way as
us in the beginning they are the same as
us I always think
we are slow students yes even though
the back of the class
December is always creative and the
students who sit in the front of the class
and in America usually the people who
like to raise their hands first
are like Siddhartha Maitreya
manjusri they have all graduated
Okay and we are like the
slow kids in class but we can still
catch up
and teachings like this will
help us to catch up with them you
and I we will be able to live in a perfect world
You can teach others too
and it will be very fun
to do it together
on the desktop and I really like
this format
angels talking on one side and
demons talking on the other side because
all day in our minds it is always
like that we have angels
talking in one place and demons
talking on the other side all
day and in the ancient book abhidharma
they say that
[Music] it is
very possible to read
other people's minds if you meditate
very well  then you can
do it if your Prana is very
good if you can do yoga
for example then you can learn to
read other people's minds but it's not
always fun you know maybe
you think this is fun but
actually it's not actually a bit
sad because we can
listen to the arguments in everyone's mind the
chaos in people's minds we can
listen to
the more drivers it won't be
a fun thing because we
all have
because we all have demons and have
angels who always talk
every day
cemen Najah n
Who are about swimmers
Screamo times Indonesia has three more sessions
Maybe three times in 2 years
so the team and I can read this and
we can publish it
wechsler in Diamond cutter published
a I think this and we will need to
write a commentary
or introduction to this book because it's
very difficult
I will talk a little about the
author of this book
he was once on a retreat
in a cave
if you have ever been on a long retreat
you know that people will cook for
you because you are not allowed to go out you
can't buy food at the market
then
this author also Has someone
who will buy food for Him
And He and this person communicates
through notes they are not allowed to
talk to each other
then this person who is shopping
comes to the cave and writes something Hi
who  said that bad news you
have to move from here
and panchen lama wrote back why
and sip this shopper
said there will be a war in this place
there is a war here and tomorrow there will
be
22 Generals who brought two groups of
soldiers coming here And there will be a lot of
fighting going on here fighting
and you have to get out of here you
can't be in this cave anymore
Then you can imagine
panchen lama is
like us he said Wow it's
so scary I have to run at night
more
posts by
BTS which krishand teh have to
pack
my meditation pillow then I have to
run far away I think if panchen
lama was like us we would think the
same thing then he also couldn't sleep
and He started thinking
Wow if tomorrow people fight in
this valley then a lot of people will
die
and that's not a good thing I have to
do something
and I was very happy
that panchen lama in the morning
he canceled his retreat then he
wrote a
note to the shopper
to ke ke for him there was at that time
he was
quite a famous lama
and he said tomorrow
or today a little later
bring me two bags of gold coins
then we have to try to
stop this war
and when the soldiers started coming
to fight he came out of his
cave then  he ran to the battlefield
and he stood between the two camps at
that time he was already a
fairly famous teacher
he said If you want to
kill one another You
have to kill me first I'm not going
anywhere
both camps respected him very much
then he said both generals are happy
Hey there come here let's
talk then the two Generals
came out and went down to the battlefield
panchen lama said Come on male sit
I have a suggestion regarding this war
and the General said what is your suggestion
then he said
you know I am a fairly
famous lama and people always
offer me money offer
gold here I have two big bags
full of
gold coins and my suggestion is
I give one bag to this General
and
I will give the other bag to the
other General then Come on
you guys just go home and relax
don't fight
Hey
fortune then the two Generals were very
happy carrying the two bags of coins
then they went home and everyone was
happy it was
very easy to finish the
war I really like
him He is very clever and he is very
brave an extraordinary thinker
So I will read
Let's read the verses he wrote
Okay likes to tell stories so grandfather if you
invite him can't hurry up
okay our team will have  a
rather short session and also there are two
sessions today and also a Q&A session
so in about 20 minutes
we will receive the
earrings Is that okay Yes
okay
then we will take a short break so
I can finish the shoot
Veronica my wife
yustisi I would like to use
this teaching
to
invite all my friends in
Sedona Arizona to come with
Salma
and it
would be great if we
taught together at the
University we can Dona but
maybe I feel like I can still
transmit covert to others
even though I feel healthy and Teh is
finished but I don't want to
spread anything to others
so it's better to do this at home
I apologize
unit cycles #encounter when it's safe
later we can sit together at the
University
Let's read this please DPRD is said to be the
trigger Mr Journey toward the Innocence
of valetic
Okay
electrofisher Let's read one
by one
in Buddhism we say that
If you die and in
your life you are very generous with
your possessions if you share a lot then the
square foot of your first perfection
is charity or sharing or giving
If you like charity giving
your money not giving your time
giving your wisdom with
other people
then when you
die you will be reborn
as a God and God means
Faith When you think about Iron
Man Superman
Fantastic Four
them or Store they are all like
Gods and I think
those movies were made by humans
who are remembering their
past lives I think the people who
made those movies
they are remembering
their past lives so when we plant
very good seeds by
sharing with others then when
we die we will
enter a realm like heaven which is
temporary of
course
we feel a bit dangerous too yes Because
at that time people can still
die and use Karma Karma
good
so when we watch those movies
we can't meet the council
directly we don't have a power
to do that we can only
watch in movies but actually people
like that exist
so when you can meet
them
you will feel that their power
is like a pen
Twitter they can fly in the sky
then they can
fight bad guys
that is typical is that it comes from
themselves and their power comes from the
Pen And in their whole life and
in
their previous lives
Oh yes if you are listening to
me today then you have a past life
if something can happen
once then it can happen a
second time
if there is  Your computer or your car
is not working then you have to
fix it immediately because you
wait it will not get
better If your car makes
noises Yang ati ikhlas or
your computer is doing something
wrong then you have to
fix it So if a problem
can happen once then it can happen
three times or even 1000 times so
you don't be lazy If you can live
now if you can be born
here once come on
don't be stupid
if your car can break down on Monday
then
your car can still break down
on Tuesday then If you have
come or been born in this world
once then you have been born
here twice or a million times because
time is limitless
when we read this story
from a teacher we trust
station that there are teachers who are very
generous they share what
they think and after they
die their
seeds create the
form of a
storm God creature set then he said that
it was a scheme in the wedding
Hihihi indeed if God comes from
oneself like a pen comes from a pen
then Why can they die and
why is there a God's life that can
end
and they can go to another realm Hi
if this pen
comes from himself then  he
will never run out of ink it is
impossible if the pen comes from
himself then he will never
run out of ink
if someone
islami.co on-site comes from himself
then they cannot die and
cannot change that is what the angel said
so
I like today's class and
tomorrow's class
because the angel doesn't
talk too much maybe the angel is shy yeah
maybe many angels are shy
but in this part he doesn't
talk too much he says Let's
see if this Philippines comes from a
pen here though
So if people come from
themselves then how can people
die
Oh that means
how can they die and be
reborn so
this whole poem that we are talking about today
and tomorrow
they will
discuss How can it happen How can it
happen
Awe dies then what happens
to us after we die this
is a very strange thing
When I went to
Princeton University one of the
best investments in the whole world and I
felt right
I spent 4-5 years There
was no class there
about How do you die very then
in the whole University
much more once sex.com Doors they
have
36 Billion Dollars every year in
funding for them but there was no class
about how do we die
because it is very amazing  even though
everyone has to leave
this like
building an entire University but
not given a class
there is not given a bathroom because
sooner or later you have to go to the
bathroom but if we build a
big building without a bathroom it is
very stupid that means people
can not think ahead
the phenomenon of not being able to think 23 years 23
hours from now You will definitely need a bathroom
everyone needs a bathroom
in Indonesia itself
Yusuf Pesantren care When you
build a university Of course
you have to build a toilet there too
and If you teach
people about life then you
have to teach about death too
or this will not be a
complete university Okay So the Angel said
if you come from yourself
How can you die
So if you
continue life Next what
happens to you we have to
ask this and we have to be interested
in this if someone says
take your bag take your suitcase
He said where am I going Don't
worry we will go
When will we go oh in a few years
anyway you Sir just a
taste You
if you don't ask Where do you
expect to go and where will you
take your bag then you are very
you are crazy
Yesterday I was 35 now I am
65 now my hair is also
like this I was very
shocked
what  what happened we all have to
get ready we won't be
here forever
The more najwa.com okay what can we
do
when that happens to us Hai
Mbak ed242qr
mebeljogja
gender jodoh then
the devil said
Look everyone dies and everyone
will go somewhere when
they die  ggal Why because you
came here also from somewhere it's
impossible if you
died Then you just disappeared
Of course you'll go
somewhere you've come here right
old history icon if So if something can
happen once it can happen
again sometime
big Tegal that's indecent then the devil
said no no no
people do die
FB is not nice and they everyone
continues their life and is
reborn
ITC
then the angel said if
the pen is from you then you
are also from yourself If
you are from
yourself then you will not be able to
change
Well that's a pretty difficult idea
if the pen
comes from itself as
we think
then it will never change and will never run
out of ink if
the ink is in the pen then the pen
will never run out of ink and
we have to prove it first because
by listening to it once it's
as if it doesn't go in well Gisela
adjusted my cellphone
I just said this pen comes from the
factory people make it then I
bought it in the shop
but I didn't say that the pen can't
change you know
That's why we have to buy it again in the
shop when it runs out
then gecella told you
this yes if the pen originally came from the
shop
if the pen was made in the factory then he
can't change
and can't run out of ink but
gecella I didn't say that
of course the pen is made in a factory
When you write this the ink comes out
of the pen then sticks to the paper and
the ink runs out I
want it to change
but I didn't say that
the pen can change but you don't ask
where the pen came from you don't
ask why this pen
came to me this is a
big thing that is important If you want to
have a happy life
and a successful death it's very strange
yes that word yes a happy life
and a successful death or a
successful one You have to ask
where you came from Not How did
you come to this world but
Why did you come to this world
If you ask me
how this pen came to Hi
to the shop then I will explain Oh
this is
a the materials are imported from Japan
then put into the factory then the
factory sends it to the shop this is
Why the pen came I said no
This is how the
pen came not Why
How did the pen come
oh made in the factory
Oh shipped imported to America Then
you buy gecella okay I understand that is
why that is how the
pen came but why me Why did
this pen come to me Oh Come on
Islam they make thousands of
pens every day no need to ask
like that there is no answer yes hi
okay that's why your hair is
falling out gecella Because you ask
things that don't make sense don't
think about it anymore Kai is just a
questioner
but if you are a smart person
you should ask Why is
your car broken today why is your car
making strange sounds now
then Why is my computer broken
oh the answer is not
because I have driven it too
far then it is broken but that's not the
correct question is Why is
my car broken because the team car is
not broken Stanley's car is not broken
Cheezy's car is not broken but why is
my car broken then I said that
and there are smart people
too reasons Why do you have to ask
Why me if how is it easy
How is your engine broken oh the
carburetor is dirty a That's why
your car makes
strange sounds but that's not it don't tell
me how tell me Why is
my car's carburetor broken but the
team car's car size is not Come on you
have to ask this question is very
important
more important than anything you
planned today
like me I have to go to University
then I have to have a tribal period for my wife
we ​​planned from this morning what we
want to do Hi but
on the day for sure Where are you  have to
face death you will die
Have you ever planned
I don't know now
if the sub will burn or not
but what I know for sure I
will die so we have to be
prepared and we have to ask
Why we die and not
how we die
and that's what we will do
in the next class
Okay Uncle team
Are you going to
open a Q&A session
feels like there will be 15 minutes Seven liquid
Q&A
we will a.mom open a Q&A session
but yes kyles Why are people extreme
Why do bald people like Zoom yes
because you can cut off the top of
your head like I'm doing
now this is the
first question gecella by
understanding the Pen Story we know that
everything comes from ourselves
even though the money is
Telkomsel kebab explain virens how
we apply this to people
who experience domestic violence then people
who suffer
too is now I love you that is a
very good question
You know I lived in a
Mongolian monastery in New York for 25 years
but in Trump there are a lot of
Mongolian monks and nuns and I
lived there with my teacher 25
years I came from Princeton
Actually I should have been
a Christian priest because I
was accepted into  school
to study to become a priest in
Princeton there is a very beautiful Cathedral
which is
similar to Notre Dame Cathedral in
Paris and the music is also very beautiful
header success and the place is very beautiful
and the building is very expensive
then
from Princeton I went straight to
kwill Mongolia
and there are many
beautiful statues of Tarra Maitreya Buddha
But there are also
very scary paintings
like paintings of hell
and the music is spice
[Applause]
n I can't meditate because the
music is like World War II
Let me tell my teacher
How can you have
paintings like this which are very
scary and the music here is very loud
How can you meditate then
my teacher said every culture has its
own way
in Mongolia this is like a church
this is more of a culture here this is
also beautiful and this is also okay
different from your culture in printscreen
Then there is something like a stage on the
stage there is a Swastika the stage
where the teacher sits the
swastika is a symbol of rice
which started a war that killed
130000000 people in the world then here there is
I saw there is a Swastika but it
turns out the swastika sign originated from
India
di-ping Sallam and it is
actually has the meaning of longevity
and they always put it on the
teacher's chair
for 2000 years before Hitler or the
Nazis used it Hi and he
explained everything to me
and I said okay okay it makes perfect
sense that Hitler borrowed
this symbol
Then one day there were Jews who
came to our temple and I thought
oh my God this is going to be a big problem
it was
my job because I was the
youngest monk so I
had to explain them I took them for a
walk around the temple
but before they came my teacher
said you know
hide the Swastika
take it off and put it under the chair don't
show it I said Why
then my teacher said they won't
understand they will think we are
bad people people like
Nafsi so just hide it don't
show it then I said Ah no no it's
okay I'll
explain to them then my teacher
bidang maybe we can't
Explain to him they they have
seen this symbol all their life even though
They listen to you but they
still in themselves won't feel
comfortable in our temple
so just hide it then I
hid it then a They were
happy to be in the temple they
enjoyed their walk there then
I gave it back  The swastika on the
chair Why am I telling
this in Buddhism we understand
that
there are times when yes no students are not
ready there are times when we do not need to
talk about something because students are
not ready and I believe Why
children can die in fires
traffic accidents
Why do so
many people
experience domestic violence
or are sexually abused
physically beaten and why does it
happen what does it mean what is the reason and there
should be a reason
everything has a reason there is nothing
in this universe that does not have a
cause
everything has a reason
don't ask me
how
hello ah those children were hurt Oh
They went somewhere Then there was a
bad person who hurt them
Don't ask
how but ask why-why
this child but not that child
in Buddhism there are customary answers
to questions like that
this is Why today we are
here and we listen to this class we
feel that we can find the
real answer but
there are times when people are not ready to
listen to the reason Actually
there are times when we can only
show them review Asy affection
so lo wis
RCTI even
does not answer everything
directly when he feels the student is not
ready so yes  There is a reason why,
for example, a two-year-old child can
die in a traffic accident Then
there is also a reason why some children are
hurt and some are
fine, there is a reason for everything,
but
the bridge in our tradition,
great teachers
often say that maybe
our students are not ready to hear
the reason,
maybe it is more important to give the
students a loving hug.
You can explain about
past lives about seeds.
Hi, about the cause of
everything, but you have to choose the
right time, and when the parents of
such children are suffering,
it is not the right time to
say the reason and it is
your time to hide the Swastika. A
hug. They give
them love so they feel better,
but it is true that everything
has a cause. I
saw a
psychiatrist. How long ago did
you ask why these children
become emotional?
Because when their
mother was pregnant, she ate too
much chili sauce.
Give a damn, it's so Bene
via2, this psychiatrist explained
that
this child's mind
was a little disturbed. Is it because
her mother ate
too much terrassa chili sauce when she was pregnant? It
doesn't make sense, but what is
more important is that in my opinion, the
Buddha always
looks at
which student first.  what he is facing is
like my teacher he is also like
Buddha he told me to
hide the Swastika
so the important thing is to
teach you Hi at
their level then later when they are ready
then explain the origin of everything
for Star Wars at first agsela you
talked about how the
panchen lama stopped the war
censorship
there are questions coming in in
some countries they feel the threat of
war and They ask
from them inspired by
your story how to stop
the war in their place
yes this is a good question
when I was a student at
Princeton was when the Vietnam War
was happening
and I was very disturbed by the war
and unfortunately
I protested
the war until I
went to jail for a while
because my friend and I tried
to close a
weapons factory
but we protested peacefully
we sat in front of the factory door and
we did not allow the workers
to enter and produce weapons then
the Police came and arrested us and
put us in jail for a
while and I also never
forget I once met
other students or students
And we tried to stop
this war
there were 1000 people in
this student meeting
head coil really les until someone
said Let's just bomb Hey
Chancellor's office we will show them
that we can  stop the war then
I raised my hand and said
wait wait I don't understand
It seems like you're doing the same thing
bombing Vietnam
and to keep Vietnam from being bombed
you want to bomb the school I was very
disturbed by this I thought it was the
same thing
then
my channel felt hopeless and I
thought I've been
trying for 4-5 years to
stop the Vietnam war but it didn't have
much impact
then I said Oh one person can't
do much I'm also
10,000 miles away from the six I
also don't know how I can
stop this war then I felt
Hopeless then I didn't act about
not doing much after that
but after that I learned about
emptiness with my teacher then I
learned about
Karma I learned about how
seeds open I started observing
my surroundings around me my world
all comes from myself
like this pen
more that I can see conflict
see this war all comes
from myself like
I
was listening to the news last night
about a problem well
then we
Oh the problem I'm listening to
actually comes from myself
and because it comes from me I
can help solve it So you
never give up
If the pen theory is true then you
will never be
helpless  you can always help
everyone in the world can help
resolve conflict Everyone can
resolve conflict quesella how am
I just one person What can I
do
but still
this conflict tension all comes back
to the pen
for everyone for the whole world it
comes from each of us
each of
us has planted the seeds
for these conflicts and that's why
we see it in
our world because it comes from ourselves
because it comes from ourselves
one person
can do something I don't have to
process with other people at
school I don't have to bomb the
school eh don't have to go to jail
but I can help this situation
how do we see
people who are not
communicating with each other
They each don't want to
communicate with each other
they think about themselves then
they don't want to think about each
other we see that because we
plant seeds like that because
all I think about is
myself and I don't
pay attention to other people there are so
many
millions of people who can't eat
every day
and I have so much food
so much
so I can stop the war
Aya can stop the conflict if I
start by
planting seeds from myself
if I meet someone and
there are people who feel threatened by
my existence  Indeed I do not want
to hurt others
Maybe there are people who need
attention I need affection
I need me to calm
him WiFi if
I personally come and reach out to
people like that
especially people who feel
threatened by my presence
Celine debit washing dosage if I
reach them Then I cancel the
seeds that I have so that I
no longer see any
tensions or conflicts around me
so what you see around you is
originally from your own seeds
left yesterday capoue ah today too
Call one person who is in
conflict with you
give affection to people who
feel that you are trying to hurt
them
convince them that you
love them Then it will
cancel the seeds So you no
longer see conflict
Khoir Syukron Lifehouse You can
see
how the future of your life is
You can pay attention to
your seeds and you can change
your world by paying attention to the seeds that are
currently planted
okay okay must check the shop